okay let's get started so the main topic
for today is naive Bayes models but the
real context here is that today will be
our first lecture on machine learning up
until now we have been assuming that
somebody gives us a model they give us a
search problems they give us a search
problem their weights on the edges
there's a game there's probabilities of
the chance nodes we have a Bayes net and
there's a bunch of conditional
probabilities that we use to do
computation with and we've looked at how
to use that model to make optimal
decisions whether that's thinking about
sequencing actions in the first part of
the course or managing inferences over
uncertainty in the second part of the
course and now we're gonna shift gears
and look at machine learning which is
about how to acquire a model how to
acquire the parameters of a model from
data and experience so in the end we
want to build good systems there are
both accurate systems where do you get
accurate systems you you get them from
good models and good models come from
good data and we're gonna look at that
last part now so what are the kinds of
things we could learn we could learn
parameters these are the individual
numbers and other details that determine
exactly how our model works for example
the probabilities that live in each
conditional probability table of a Bayes
net that's an example of parameters we
can learn structure so we could learn
for example given a bunch of random
variables and then a bunch of data
showing observations of those random
variables we could learn something about
correlations or maybe even causation
between those variables and use that to
build a Bayes net we can also learn
hidden concepts we can take data we can
cluster that data we can look for
patterns neural nets which are a very
big topic in machine learning now are in
a lot of ways all about learning hidden
representations and hidden concepts
we're gonna do today is we're gonna
start with model-based classification
and as an example of that we're gonna
work through some details
how the naivebayes models work then in
the next few lectures we're going to
work through a sequence of different
takes on machine learning there are
gonna highlight different different
subsets of the big ideas on this topic
so today we're going to talk about
classification we have a couple running
examples one of them is that spam
classifier that pulls out all the emails
you don't want from your email another
one we're gonna look at is digit
recognition
these are simple classification problems
in some ways
right the inputs are served well
understood and the outputs are well
understood but we can already see a lot
of the big ideas in machine learning and
you could also see how something like
spam classification starts to give you a
little bit of a window and tell other
natural language tasks work and
something like digit recognition will
start to give you a window into how
other vision tasks work and we'll see
more in-depth examples and more
structured examples of these kinds of
problems later when we talk about
applications so here's an example of a
spam filter this is an example of a
classification system classification is
not the only kind of machine learning
but it's probably the biggest so
classification has an input and an
output and the whole point is to
automate the prediction of the output on
the basis of the input so the input
might be an email and the output is the
decision is the spam or is this a good
email which people work on spam call ham
so how would this work well first we
need some data and we'll see today
exactly how data kind of goes through
the mill and gets turned into a model
but you need data to learn what is a
good email what is a spam email and so
you need to get a large collection of
these in practice in the real world
getting the right kind of data is often
one of the hardest parts of building and
deploying a machine learning system so
where are we going to get a large
collection of example emails well we
could take some email accounts get
people to agree to let us look at those
emails have humans hand label them
that's one way you could also build a
kind of an ecosystem and that naturally
generates
this data for example a lot of you in
your email accounts see spam you mark
that as spam and congratulations you've
just labeled some training data
for a classifier somebody has to hand
label this data and that can be
expensive or it can just fall out of the
ecosystem that you have around you and
how easy it is to deploy machine
learning systems often depends on how
natural it is to collect that data or to
discover that data how costly what you
have to do in order to make that data
reasonable to produce we're not gonna
talk about a lot about that in this
class but when you actually get into the
real world and you're thinking about
deploying machine learning systems data
is often the first thing and the biggest
thing you worry about so how are we
going to make these decisions well we
have a bunch of data like what's shown
on the right I'll read you some of these
these are from an actual these are from
an exact actual corpus collection of
data that's labeled that people use this
one is relatively small and it's an
older corpus but this is a corpus of
email that people use to test this
problem so here's here's one you guys
see s 188 classifier using the
parameters in your head we're gonna
decide spam or ham dear sir first I must
solicit your confidence in this
transaction this is by virtue of its
nature as being utterly confidential and
top-secret what do you think spam it
looks really important yeah it's spam
here's next one to be removed from
future mailings simply reply to this
message and put removing the subject 99
million email addresses for only $99
spam I mean that's like a million email
addresses per dollar yeah that's bad you
don't want that one
all right okay I know this is blatantly
off-topic but I'm beginning to go insane
had an old Dell Dimension XPS sitting in
the corner and decided to put to you so
I know it was working pre being stuck in
the corner but when I plugged it in hit
the power nothing happened hammer spam
yeah so this is him whether you
personally wish to receive this email
this is between you and your friends
right but this is an email that was
intentionally sent from somebody who
probably knows the the recipient here
and you would have to go through and
label this in the case of email it's
very very much an individual question
which emails you want to receive or not
and so the the boundary between what is
actually spam unsolicited commercial
email whatever and emails you just don't
want this is gonna be a fuzzy boundary
and this is a problem when people are
just clicking the spam
but some people just click that on an
email they wish the people hadn't sent
them even if it's like from their mom
how are you gonna make this decision
that you all just did so effortlessly
what is it about the top two emails that
let you conclude that their spam and how
could we automate this well the machine
learning is going to do some amount of
work but something has to power this
there has to be something about those
first emails that's gonna give you the
clues that something's fishy here and so
what kinds of features can you include
defining these features is a big part of
deploying machine learning systems so
the basic features in a task like spam
detection are the words and so they're
going to be some words that are big
giveaways that we have we have spam on
our hands so probably probably something
about only $99 that's probably a sign of
spam but it's not like those words
couldn't occur in ham or this utterly
confidential and top-secret that's
probably a that phrase is probably a bad
sign but it's not like that couldn't
occur and so each of these features is
gonna be something that you can think of
as a noisy indicator it's gonna give you
a little bit of confidence in the
probabilistic sense that perhaps their
spam here but no one of these things is
just gonna put that to rest and so what
we're gonna need to be able to do is
build a model that can aggregate that
information combine all of those little
bits of weak evidence manage that
uncertainty and then give us a
prediction so the words present spam are
really important and that's sort of the
basic first cut because these are
documents and you want to put them into
categories but there's a lot else you
can look at for example maybe any dollar
sign followed by some numbers as is is a
bad sign and that's a feature that
abstracts over individual words and you
can either put some effort into coming
up with these features or you can look
at even more advanced machine learning
techniques that would automate their
induction in this second one to be
removed from future mailings one big
sign that this is spam here is just all
caps that's a bad sign
that's no individual word being in caps
that's a bad sign it's sort of that that
aggregate feature and so that's a
feature you might want to add in
practice for actual spam detection a lot
of the evidence of spam versus ham comes
not from the word or
the content of the email in any way but
rather its relation to other things in
the ecosystem for example is the sender
of this email in your contacts well if
it is this is probably not spam even if
it's got some sort of marginal contents
has this email been widely broadcast
within a short amount of time obviously
your email account can't tell this but
your email account provider can because
they can see the behavior of similar
email emails appearing in lots of
different inboxes all at once so you're
gonna collect some amount of these
features and then some magics gonna
happen in the Middle where we're gonna
build a model and make predictions and
then out is going to pop classifications
of either spam or ham let's do another
example this example is another classic
one the inputs going to be images think
of them as a matrix a grid of pixels you
can be black and white they can be
grayscale whatever the output is going
to be a digit zero through nine what's
the setup for this we're gonna have to
collect a large number of example images
each one has to be labeled this is a 7
this is a 2 this is a 4 somebody has to
hand label all this or somebody has to
design an ecosystem where the stuff is
sort of self labeling we want to be able
to predict labels of new images that are
not the ones we've already seen ok so
that's actually it's subtle but it's
super important we are not like this is
not this is not the the sort of the
Pokemon collection task here we have to
collect every digit every image right
every image you see of a digit is going
to be unique it's gonna be at least one
pixel off of something else you've seen
so you can't just collect all the data
you can get data that is similar but
then in the end you're gonna have to
generalize and so we'll talk about how
that's going to work what features might
you use to detect digits well somebody
puts a grid of numbers your eyes and
your visual processing system is already
doing all kinds of processing and people
think about computer vision replicate
some of that processing you're doing all
kinds of processing when you look at a
digit you say oh that's a four but here
you know this one might be a zero we
could go we could label these things and
we're gonna try to teach your computer
to do the same thing what's the next one
it's probably a one I'm not like totally
sure what's the next one too
that slash is probably a 1 and then I
don't really know what that's supposed
to be and so this is actually a real
issue right there's a lot of inputs that
are really noisy and your training set
they might be hard to expensive to label
because they're noisy you might get them
wrong you might miss label them and then
your algorithms have to be robust to a
certain amount of noise in your training
set and then at test time you're gonna
make mistakes you're gonna make mistakes
because machine learning is not perfect
you're gonna make mistakes because some
inputs are just really really hard and
they're gonna look like this and we're
just not all even going to agree on what
the heck that's supposed to be so if you
wanted to make a decision that that top
thing is a zero and the next one is a
one you're probably going to look at the
pixels those are the basic features but
if you think about it that's not really
the most invariant representation
because I could take that zero and I
could just shift it a couple pixels to
the side and it's going to be an
entirely different set of pixels that
are on but it's still the same number so
people think about computer vision think
about invariances what are better
representations that if the thing gets
tilted or it's a little bit lighter or
it's or it's a little bit smaller or
bigger
it's not the exact pixels being on that
we care about but the pixels are
something we could use we could look at
other kinds of patterns we could look
how many connecting components of ink
there are what's the aspect ratio how
many loops are there it's increasingly
the case especially for problems like
this that we feed in low-level features
like pixels and higher-level features
like edges tend to get induced
increasingly more as our machine
learning methods get better at doing
that and we'll talk about that in a
couple weeks we talk about neural nets
all right there's tons of classification
tasks it's probably the most widely used
application of machine learning there's
also a lot of applications of other
things like clustering classification
you're given inputs you predict labels
or classes Y inputs are called X outputs
are called Y and there's tons of
examples of this medical diagnosis could
be classification the input is the
system the output is the diseases fraud
detection could be cincone your credit
card company there's some account
activity and you want a red-flag
accounts that are suspicious think about
all the different kinds of features you
could put in in order to make those
kinds of decisions both at the
individual transaction level and also at
the network level automatic essay
grading auto grading
this can be a machine learning problem
customer service email routing you have
a whole bunch of customer service agents
that do all different kinds of things
emails are flying into the system and
you'd like to automate the routing of
that review sentiment there's a bunch of
reviews of my product which ones are
good which ones are bad have they gotten
better in the past ten days since the
new announcement and so on you can do
that with classification language
identification here's this document what
languages is this anyway you got to do
that before you can do things like
translation of course what would you do
translation that's not a classification
tax anymore that's a much more
structured natural language processing
task where you actually need to generate
new language that means the same thing
in a different language so
classification is important at the end
of the lecture today you will have
enough information to go and build a
basic classifier but there's a whole
bunch of detail behind all this
the first thing we're gonna do is talk
about model-based classification
remember we talked about reinforcement
learning we talked about model-based
reinforcement learning and model free
reinforcement learning there's gonna be
a very similar distinction in the world
of classification as well in model-based
classification rather than directly
learning from errors that you make in
the world from experience think like
reinforcement learning model free
instead we're gonna learn by building a
model from our data and then doing
inference in that model to make
predictions in the world after today
we'll look at the model free methods so
the model-based approach you're gonna
build some model in this case we're
gonna build a Bayes net and it's gonna
be a super simple Bayes net called a
naive Bayes model you build a model
where the output label and the input
features are random variables there's
gonna be some connections between them
and maybe some other variables too that
might help you build a better model
either in terms of statistical
efficiency of having sort of the
representations be more compact or
because that's that's data that's easier
for you to to elicit now you've loved
this model in which you've Bayes net and
down here somewhere are going to be your
features and up here is going to be your
class and on the basis of the features X
that you observe you're gonna predict
the class Y we can do that with
probabilistic inference variable
elimination for example so you can
instantiate your observed features
you're going to query for the
distribution of the label you care about
output conditioned on this feature you
don't get a probability out now you can
ask questions like how often does my
model get the right answer that's
accuracy you can also ask questions like
do these probabilities that are falling
out of my model are they even right some
kinds of classifiers don't even give you
probabilities they just give you a
prediction so what are the challenges
what structure should the Bayes net have
today we're going to give it the
simplest structure that could possibly
work and it turns out it often does and
then the thing we're going to mostly
talk about today is how should we learn
the parameters of a model from data once
we've decided its structure so here's
what a naive Bayes model would look like
four digits it's in fact super simple as
Bayes nets go so what we will do is we
will assume that there is one special
node it's going to be the label here
that's written as Y and that labels
domain will be the various digits 0
through 9 then they're going to be a
bunch of features what are the features
well you might have a feature for every
pixel in the grid that's binary valued
that's either on or off based on whether
it's above or below a certain threshold
so the model itself might look something
like this where the class is the cause
and it independently causes each of
those features now if you look at that
you might think that doesn't sound quite
right to me because there are
correlations between the features that
are present even when you know the class
and in this naive Bayes model of the
conditional independence assumption say
that conditioned on the class that
features are independent and maybe that
doesn't feel right because if I know
it's spam or if I know it's ham for sure
may our are the first two words
independent well no they're not so the
naive Bayes assumption is an extremely
radical assumption as far as
probabilistic models go but for
classification it turns out to be really
effective and it goes something like
this so if we have a single digit
recognition version of this we might
have a feature for each position of the
grid they'll all be binary valued that
means this number 1 here maps to this
feature so it'll be a big vector of
zeros and ones which is really just the
image but if my features were instead
how much ink is there on the left side
how many loops are there then there
would be zeros and ones as well but they
would no longer correspond to the the
raw image there's a lot of feature
each one hears binary valued and the
naive Bayes model is just what's drawn
here we say that we say that the
probability distribution over why the
class and all the features which
collectively basically are your input X
is the prior probability of the class
that's what lives at the node y times
the product for all of the other
variables of the probability of that
variable given its parent which is the
probability of the feature given the
class and that means when you go to make
a prediction it decomposes into a
product of a bunch of different feature
conditional probabilities and we'll see
examples with that and unpack the
inference for that ok so what do you
need in general ok that was one example
what do you need in general a general
naive Bayes model places a Joint
Distribution over the following
variables Y which is your class and some
number of features which you get to
define you're gonna have to write code
which extracts them from your input so
if your spam feature is have more than
ten people received this email in the
past hour
you have to write code which extracts
that the value of that feature but the
machine learning will do the work to
connect the probability of that taking
on a certain value up to the class in
addition the way this joint probability
is going to work is you're going to have
a prior probability of the class and
then a bunch of little conditional
probabilities which directly connect
each feature up independently to the
class so this whole network that this
whole joint distribution that we're
describing is enormous right it's going
to be exponential in a number of
features but the thing we actually build
is quite compact all we have to have is
Y parameters one for each class value
and then for each feature we need to
have a little description of how likely
that feature is for each class and
that's it so the naive Bayes model will
be linear in the number of features
whereas the joint probability
distribution that you're implicitly
describing is exponential in the number
of features so basically the thing we
have to specify is healthy each feature
depends on the class and we're going to
get that from data ok all right a couple
things to get out of the way before we
look at the actual data stuff one is
it's a model so in order to do
predictions you have to do inference
turns out you already know this there's
nothing new here in fact it's a simple
case of inference by enumeration so if I
would like to compute
the thing I actually want to compute is
the probability of Y that is the
distribution over all the different
class labels given my features that's
what I actually want to compute but I
know that I can just compute the joint
version of that Y comma the features
well what is that well if that were a
lowercase Y it would be a scalar it
would be an entry of the joint
probability table since it's a capital y
it's a vector right so it's a
one-dimensional vector here that has an
entry for each value of y so there's P
of y1 and the feature is P of Y 2 and
the features P of Y 3 and so on if I had
all of these probabilities and I
normalized I would have the conditional
probability of the class given the
features all right so this is what I'm
looking for I'm looking for this vector
of probabilities of feature and class
how do I get them well for each one of
these entries of the Joint Distribution
here I can rewrite it according to my
Bayes net which is going to be a product
of all these little local probabilities
it's the product each one is the product
of a prior probability of the class
which says whether or not before you see
the evidence this is a class that's
common or not and then a product of a
bunch of feature probabilities which is
how likely is this feature for this
class how likely is this feature for
that class and so on all right so you
compute all those products you normalize
them you're done okay that's it
it's just variable elimination ok so
what do we need we need an inference
method we've just seen this we have a
Bayes net in this case it's super simple
it's one that assumes all the features
are conditionally independent given the
label we need all of the component
probabilities nothing new what's new is
now we also in order to make this work
we need to know what those probabilities
are how likely is it to have the word
free in spam how likely is it that the
center pixel will be on for the number-7
these questions can only be answered by
going to data all right so the things we
need to do is we're gonna need to figure
out the prior probability over labels
and for each feature which is each kind
of evidence we're going to need to
compute a bunch of conditional
probabilities for each class these
things collectively all these
probabilities that we use to plug and
chug and get our numbers out
called the parameters of the model
formally they're usually denoted by
theta and as I change the parameters of
the model it still say a naive Bayes
model over spam versus ham but as I
change the probability different things
are gonna blink in and out as I think
this is spam now I think this is him now
so those numbers collectively are going
to determine which predictions it makes
so it has to come from data which
parameters we want all right let's see
some examples of what these conditional
probabilities and naive Bayes model
would look like so here's an image maybe
this is the number three the first thing
we need in order to apply naive Bayes to
this is we need a prior probability over
the class and so in this particular
vector in these parameters each class
one to zero is equally likely what do
you think it is in real if I went to
like a real collection of data well I
could get a thousand examples of the
number three and a thousand examples of
number four and a thousand examples the
number five probably I should just get
like a million or as many as I can get
of each number if I constructed the data
set in that way well then all these
prior probabilities would be equal
because in my data 10% of the examples
or one and 10% of the examples are -
what do you think's real which number do
you think is most common in real data or
they all equally common so zero might be
common depends of the kind of data
you're looking at if you're looking at
ZIP codes in California what's the most
common thing it's nine if you're looking
at lots of round numbers maybe at zero
if you're looking at sort of general
numbers it turns out one is particularly
common you can think about why that
might be so so these come from data and
this actually underscores the point that
depending on how you collect the data it
can actually shape the distributions
that you are imagining are gonna exist
at test time and we'll come back to that
as well when we talk about risk
minimization all right in addition to
the prior probability of each label
which is already maybe a little tricky
to get right in our data we can compute
things like what is the probability that
pixel 3 comma 1 is on given each class
this isn't a distribution over on or off
these are just the probabilities what
I'm showing here just
of that pixel for each class and it's
going to be some number so for example
the pixel on that position might be
pretty likely for the number six but
pretty rare for the number one and these
probabilities will encode that okay and
you'll have that for each of the
different pixels so this is what the
conditional probabilities in the naive
Bayes model look like where did they
come from
well this number came from saying all
right in all of my examples of numbers
that are the number five how often was
pixel three one on okay 80% of them done
that comes from the data this works a
little bit differently in practice when
people look at models for text so when
you look at models of something like an
image where you have a bunch of these
pixels but you know a pixel here in a
pixel there I mean very different things
the standard model for texts is to say
that the the features are the words and
that the random variables are the words
at each position so you would say
something like well I have a joint
probability over the class which could
be spam or ham or document classes or
positive or negative sentiment or
whatever along with the rest of the
document the words the standard way to
write that there in a naive Bayes model
is to say that's the prior probability
of the class and then the product of
across each position in the document
probability of the word at that position
given the class and so again this is a
naive Bayes model and but the random
variables now are not something like
we're they're not the presence or
absence of individual words they're the
product across each position in the
document of what word is at that
position so this is actually interesting
because I have in the in the image case
I had lots and lots of features because
it's a big grid but each one was either
on or off right with a document one they
can be of any length and to each
position has a large event space there's
a whole bunch of words that can be at
position 23 in the document but for the
purposes of detecting spam versus ham it
doesn't really matter whether a word
occurs at position 23 or 24
right when you see print cartridge which
is I guess two words at a certain
position it probably doesn't matter what
position it's in and so for these people
look at models which have an even
stronger assumption they assume not only
are the features conditionally
independent of each other given the
class they also assume that they're
identically distributed and that means
the probability distribution over the
words at position 23 and the probability
distribution over the words at position
54 are the same single probability
distribution and that means for a naive
Bayes model for text the only thing you
actually have to learn is for each class
what is the histogram of words what is
the probability distribution over words
in that class these are tied
distributions this is called a bag of
words model and this is different than
the standard case because in the
standard case each feature gets its own
distribution here we assume the features
are all identically distributed but
there are multiple copies of that
feature for the different positions and
this is nice because when the document
is longer or shorter you don't really
need to change your modeler or it is the
first time you've had a document that is
you know one word longer than the
longest thing you've ever seen you're
like oh man what is that last word mean
right it's the same as it means in any
other position okay let's do an example
of of spam filtering here in this bag of
words model for text which means the
probability over the class and the words
is the product of the probability of the
class times the probability of each word
independently given the class and
remember the words are identically
distributed so I just go through and
each word that comes in is gonna get a
probability for each class and there's
gonna be a race to see which class wins
in terms of probability so what am I
gonna do I'm gonna have to see the words
that come in but I'm gonna in the end
compute two things I'm gonna compute the
probability of spam along with all of
the words and I'm gonna compute the
probability of ham along with all the
words and then those will be numbers
they won't sum to one in fact they're
gonna be really really small numbers you
multiply a hundred probabilities
together you get a small number small
enough that you would have to worry
about underflow in practice so we're
going to compute these probabilities
whichever one is
bigger that's gonna be my prediction if
I want to know the probability that I
assign I would have to renormalize have
to take these two numbers and divide
them by their sum so let's do it let's
see we're gonna compute incrementally as
the words come in position by position
we're gonna compute probability of spam
and the words probability of ham and the
words so here we go so let's look at the
the let's look at the teh the the tables
first I will give you this one actually
maybe I should have hidden it it turns
out in this corpus two-thirds of the
emails are ham and one-third of them are
spam how would you say this relates to
the emails you get do you get more spam
than this or less probably a lot more so
spam has gotten worse since this corpus
was collected and again this underscores
that just because some there's some
distribution that your data reflects and
then there's the real world and you want
those to be as close as possible if
there's major major systematic ways in
which your data and the distribution it
was drawn from in its construction do
not match the distribution in the real
world that you're gonna field your
classifier against you're gonna have
issues one major issue you can have is
reduced accuracy all right
so for these others if I'm gonna build a
naive Bayes model for spam filtering I
need to collect the prior which is gonna
turn out to be less important than the
other components and then I need to
compute for spam what is the histogram
of words and for ham what is the
histogram afford so let's look at the
spam one first what do you think is the
most frequent word in spam I heard free
what else any other guesses
I heard the you laughs but here's the
answer what's going on here I thought
free meant spam this is not an odds
ratio this is not words that are much
more likely in spam than ham this is
simply in this model the probability of
word given class and then spam the most
likely word is the somewhere far down
that list is the word free how about for
ham what do you thinks the most likely
word
yeah it's thought to so these it turns
out that if you just look with a couple
weird exception
like 2002 any guesses when this corpus
was collected if you just look at the
most common words this is not where the
information is in fact the information
in a model like this is in the relative
probabilities because they're going to
be this race that I talked about here
that we're going to be cumulating two
probabilities and as we go the joint
probability is going to drop because
this particular message is not
particularly likely under the document
for either class but for one of the
classes it's going to be relatively
speaking meaning the ratio is going to
be much more likely and so what matters
is actually the relative the the ratio
of these frequencies so somewhere down
there is the word free which is
presumably much more likely in the span
all right so where these tables come
from they come from data let's do that
example I promised you so we're sitting
here where the spam classifier we're a
naive Bayes classifier and we are going
to produce a joint probability by
multiplying in evidence terms as the
words come in right now notes words have
come in which means we only have one
term in our product which is the prior
probability of each class so right now
our running total here would be 0.33 for
spam and point six six for ham which
means if you asked me now I would say
that's ham and if you ask me how
confident I was I would say I predict
two-thirds chance of ham all right
the terms that are going to show up on
the left here are going to be the
evidence terms for each word as it comes
in the thing on the right here is the
product of all of these terms what - 1.1
it's not just gonna be the product
because that product is gonna get very
small very quickly it is going to be the
log of the product okay so so far we
think it's ham because the log of that
product is higher alright next word
comes in Gary
remember Gary is not particularly likely
under either distribution this is a
generative model and that means that
we're gonna have the probability of the
features given the evidence and Gary is
not particularly likely for either ham
or spam but what is it more likely for
it's much more likely in ham right
direct address actually knowing who
you're writing to that's much more
likely in ham but it's not particularly
likely there
why most people aren't named Gary all
right but if you look suddenly now if
you stopped me and you said okay right
now it's time to make a prediction ham
or spam what would I pick I would pick
ham because there's a bigger number
right there they're negative because
they're logs of probabilities and if you
ask me how confident I was I would say
I'd much more confident I'm 10 times
more confident than I was before because
I've seen this word Gary alright Gary
would this is one of those words that's
actually quite common but it's not you
know that asymmetric it doesn't change
my beliefs that much you can think about
these as belief updates think back to
the hmm evidence is coming in my beliefs
update as I multiply in terms of
probability maybe makes me think a
little more ham because wood is one of
those nice harmless common words that
occurs in natural texts Gary would you
uh oh you as a mildly suspicious word
it's super common but it turns out it's
a little bit more common in spam but you
can see how like it's not like I'm gonna
delete every email that has the word you
in it so we get little bits of weak
evidence that need to get aggregated in
this model of the way they're aggregated
is multiplying their conditional
probabilities Gary would you like to
lose weight while you sleep and then
once you've seen the whole email and you
look at the end you'll notice two things
one the total probability is very small
because I multiplied to a bunch of
probabilities that's fine that's always
true in Bayes net inference I have to I
have to divide both of these very small
numbers by their sum to get the
conditional posterior that I want and if
you look at this now it thinks it's spam
somewhere in there somewhere around lose
weight it changed its mind you can see
weight is a pretty strong indicator
apparently so is sleep okay so this
one's like to be a naive Bayes model
features come in you aggregate all of
the weak evidence and then you output
another nice thing even though it's sort
of you got to take a step back to see it
is that there was actually conflicting
evidence on this example there was some
evidence that was ham and there's some
evidence of spam there's a bunch of
examples of both and this all needed to
be weighed and that's what's going on
here in the conditional model all right
probability of span
98.9 gary was off to a good start but i
went downhill from there any questions
yep no the questions can use the log for
the final it's actually very common when
you're multiplying probabilities to just
add log probabilities instead in the end
when you want to turn it into
probabilities you do need to sum them
and summing the logs won't do that you
need to do a sort of log sum which one
way to do that is to convert them back
to two two probabilities by taking
Exponential's that's actually not the
way you would do it you would sort of
shift them by their minimum or their
maximum as appropriate so that you don't
get underflow so when you actually do
these things you got to worry about that
but conceptually you multiply all the
probabilities you get a small number and
then you renormalize yep
yep it's a great question
here's another model here's why your
class here's word one word two word
three word four and so on I can assume
that each word depends on the class and
also the previous word what am i can
probabilities look like well except for
the beginning and I can get rid of that
by having a start symbol sort of the
workhorse term for this model is what is
the probability of word kay given word K
minus one and the class okay this part
without the class is what's called a
bigram model you're predicting words
based on the previous word so you're
looking at by two words at a time and
now we've made it conditional on a class
this is a better model of language if
you started if you did prediction in
this and you started with the class and
you cranked out a pretend document it
would look significantly more like a
real email than if you just did a bag of
words where it'd just be a bunch of like
English looking words in some random
order however will it be more accurate
for classification it really depends in
general it'll be a little more accurate
but at a cost of having significantly
more complicated conditional
probabilities to estimate how much more
accurate will depend on to what degree
the bag of words assumption is dangerous
so if I take a spam document and I
permute all the words randomly I've
definitely like it is no longer
syntactically valid English but it's
probably still spam right in the same
way like I take a document that's a
sports document and if I'm doing sports
versus politics and I permute the words
and now it's like this whole mess of
words I can't read it but it's like you
know it's like goal team win right it
still hasn't changed and so if you're
looking for a class which is not kind of
strongly connected to the actual
ordering knife phase is really good
otherwise you add other correlations
like this to fix it okay other questions
you're good questions all right
a couple more general slides and then
we'll take a break
so actually change my mind let's take a
break now we are now into the machine
learning section which means we are done
with the spooky Halloween time ghost
busting section but I have candy so
during the break everybody got up and
come grab candy if you would like this
gets applause I come up and grab some
please I'm not allowed to take it home
all right we're gonna get started again
let me say your candy consuming I would
rate as middle-of-the-road you can come
back up to the at the end of the class
if you would like to to grab more all
right so let's talk about training and
testing so we talked a little bit about
we want to build classifiers we're gonna
do it on the basis of data because how
the hell how the heck am I supposed to
know what pixels seven comma three is
for the number eight I got to get that
from the data how am I supposed to know
what is the probability of you know a
certain you know a certain word for a
certain class you go to a collection of
data and you and you you you find it
there but there's sort of something
missing there which is why are we doing
that we're sort of doing that because we
want to do well on the final exam what's
the final exam the final exam is this
classifier is released into your inbox
and it actually manages to find all the
spam with high accuracy so there's got
to be some connection between what's
going on in your data which is what you
have and this future used to what you're
gonna put the classifier to and a lot of
machine learning theory is really based
about based on trying to say something
precise about the connection between
those two things so we're gonna talk
about now is a couple things relating to
training the mechanics of how you do
parameter estimation in this particular
model but really the reason we're doing
this is not just for naive Bayes or
probabilistic model estimation in
general but to see examples of more
general phenomena and trade-offs and
concerns that occur in machine learning
more broadly so remember the general
setup is going to be we're gonna have a
training set we're gonna build a
classifier and we're gonna unleash it on
the world so the basic principle of
machine learning is something called
empirical risk minimization we'll get
into this in a great amount of detail in
the next few slides and then
particularly in the next couple lectures
after this one the principle of
empirical risk minimization says go
something like this
we would like to find the model
classifier whatever that does the best
whatever the best means on our true test
distribution so maybe we would like to
find somehow get the naive based BAM
classifier which is most accurate at
finding spam in real people's inboxes
today we don't actually know that true
distribution like we don't actually know
what its gonna see at test time in the
same way that when you go to your final
exam you don't actually know what
questions you're gonna get you don't
know what distribution they're going to
be drawn from so how do you make
progress well what you do know is you
have a training set and you can't pick
the parameters which are going to do
best for your true test distribution so
instead we try to pick the best model on
our training set and hope there's a
connection between those two finding the
best model on your training set is
usually phrased at some level as an
optimization problem today we're going
to appeal more to just directly
estimation of probabilities but by the
time we get to optimization based
methods over the next couple lectures
you'll see this more generally it's
usually an optimization problem optimize
some quantity on my training set in the
hopes that that quantity will remain
optimized on the test set or at least
nearly so so what can go wrong here the
main worry and this will be a little
abstract now we'll see some concrete
examples coming up the main worry is
that you over fit the main worry is that
in picking the parameters of your model
for example the probabilities of various
words on the basis of your training data
you do a really good job of capturing
that training data but it doesn't
generalize this is like you download all
the exams from past years and you
optimize you learn all those answers and
then you go to the the final exam and
it's totally totally different questions
that look nothing like those that's
going to be a problem so you worry about
overfitting
now there's ways you could all there's a
couple different things that can go
wrong here
one thing that can go wrong when you
deploy a classifier
is the training distribution does
actually represent the test distribution
right so those practice exams were
written by the same people for the same
course or whatever as the test exam but
you didn't actually have enough you just
had a couple samples here and those
samples sort of didn't really shine
light over the whole space of things
that you might encounter that's a
problem of not enough training data so
we try to get as much training day as we
can what else could go wrong you could
have a ton of practice exams but you
could you could over fit as a learner
you could just rote memorize those
examples those test questions you get to
your final exam and you're like wait
it's not one of the ones I memorized
okay there the problem might not be with
a training set that or the problem is
the the learning the learning over fit
to the training set how do we limit that
mechanically we limit that in a couple
ways we limit the complexity of your
hypotheses we'll be able to say
precisely what that means later we
penalize sort of overly specific models
in various kinds of ways and we'll see
some examples of that even today and
then there are other ways this can go
wrong so one way so how can you do badly
on the on the final exam you can have
not enough training data and there's
just no way to have sort of seen the
whole space you can have plenty of
training data but you can sort of learn
in a way that fails to generalize and
then you can have tons of data drawn
from the wrong wrong distribution what
would this mean this would be like you
study and study and study and study all
these practice exams you spend weeks
doing practice exams for CS 189 and then
you walk into the C s 188 final you're
like something's wrong here
I learned really well I understand the
concepts but it's just not lining up
okay that's that's a drift in
distribution that's where your training
examples were plentiful but they were
drawn from a distribution which does not
match the one that you're gonna see a
test time machine learning theory has
the most to say about the first few
things right how what's the danger in
having a small amount of training data
which means high sampling variance
what's the danger and having hypothesis
spaces that are either so
big that they can over fit or so small
they can't capture all what's going in
the data so things like that this idea
of the test distribution sort of being
not stationary against the training
distribution is something that's really
important in the real world and it's
much harder to say precise things about
okay let's see some important concepts
and then let's estimate some parameters
so one important concept is data these
are labeled instances for like emails
that are marked spam or ham in general
when somebody gives you a big vat of
data you're gonna split it into pieces
you take one piece and you say this is
my training set alright someday it'll
all be your training set if you want it
to be but when you're doing experiments
you're gonna try a bunch of different
things you want to see what works best
does this naive Bayes thing work maybe a
neural net okay so you're gonna take a
piece of your training set but most of
it usually and you're gonna take v-0
data and make it your training set then
you're gonna have to have a test set
which is not the real future test use
that it's going to be put once it's
deployed but you need something that is
not in your training data to check this
is why you might when you're studying
take some of those practice exams and
not look at them until right before the
exam because you need to check your
understanding and so we take our data
and we break it into training where we
learn our parameters and tests where we
check our accuracy if we check our
accuracy on the training data we will
find out it's very very high but that
won't be true for tests and in practice
there's usually other little shards of
the data that you're going to want to
have so for example one common one is
held-out data we'll see today and in
future lectures what that's for
you're gonna take your big vat of
undifferentiated training data and break
it into pieces you're gonna have
features which are these attribute value
pairs which characterize the inputs
classically these are like little pieces
of code you write to detect how many
times the word free occurs and whether
or not this email contact is in your us
and email senders in your contact list
and so on you go through an
experimentation cycle it looks something
like this
get your model and learning already and
then you're going to learn the
parameters like model probabilities on
your training set which involves
scrolling through the training set
counting things up sometimes making
predictions sometimes taking derivatives
and taking gradient steps whatever it is
you're going to
the parameters of your model which
starts off having no idea between spam
and ham you're gonna go through your
training data and after one or more
passes through you're gonna you're gonna
know your parameters
you're gonna need you have some other
things which aren't parameters
parameters are things like what's the
probability of pixel 73 for the number 8
then there's hyper parameters like do I
want to have features for the lowercased
version of the words in case I've seen
the word but never uppercase right these
are questions about is this or this or
this going to work better another kind
what more formally hyper parameters are
things like the amount of smoothing
we're going to see that today and then
you'll and usually select those on the
basis of some held out data and then
finally once you're ready to see how
your experiment turned out you take that
model and you test it on the test data
you don't want your to test your
classifiers on the data that was used to
train them because they will do
surprisingly well it's like if you go
back through and you try those same
practice exams you like wow I really
know the stuff now it's like no this was
your training data you always know your
training data the question is did you
generalize this can happen to your
classifier too so you always want to
test your performance on data that was
not used to train it however you as a
researcher are gonna be tempted to grab
that test data and look at it in great
detail and be like ah I see I got this
one wrong and there can be a slow leak
of your test data into your training
data if you're not careful so you try
not to peek at the test set and that's
another reason why we have held-out data
which gives you something you can peek
at you want to evaluate I ran 20
experiments how did they go am i doing
well is this thing good enough to
release you need to have some metric and
there's a lot of possible metrics an
easy one is accuracy for how many of
these emails did I make the correct
decision fraction of instances predicted
correctly but actually that's actually
not a great accurate that accuracy is
not a great metric for spam detection
any ideas why what's wrong with accuracy
okay so the answer was the classes
aren't balanced this could manifest
itself either as your trainings that
might not match our test set or somehow
they're not going to be equal at test
time and maybe you don't want to think
about the Inka lead was there another
there's another another comment so how
bad is it if that offer free print
cartridges sneaks into your inbox what
are you gonna do you're gonna not read
it it's okay
how bad is it if that email from your
boss makes it into your spam folder it's
pretty bad and so the actual loss or
cost of different kinds of mistakes may
not be the same it may not be symmetric
and so accuracy isn't always what you
want what you really want is you want a
utility here you want to know what was
my utility and you should have different
costs for these things and so sometimes
people do that there are also cases like
machine translation where you're always
going to be a little bit off a little
word here or there but there's a
difference between being completely off
and a tiny bit off and so there are a
lot of different metrics people have for
different kinds of tasks okay and again
we're going to talk a lot today and next
time about overfitting and
generalization we want a classifier
which does well on the test data we
don't have the test data or we don't
have the true test data so instead we
build a classifier that does well on the
training data and then we try to come up
with methods where the training accuracy
is gonna mean something about the test
accuracy overfitting means fitting the
training data very closely but not
generalizing well there's also the
opposite which is under fitting where
you're just like I don't know what's
going on I'm just guessing randomly
everywhere that's not over fit it's not
gonna work very well the problem here is
not that your test date your test
accuracy is low but they're training
accuracy was also local you didn't learn
anything we will investigate these
things formally in a few lectures I had
a really good question during the break
which I want to answer for everybody
which is couldn't you just defeat this
naive Bayes spam classifier by pasting
the word Gary a hundred times to the end
of your offer to lose weight while you
sleep the answer is yes
you could and I don't know whether folks
here remember but you know about ten
years ago there was a period of time
where all this spam I would get would
have like chapters of Pride and
Prejudice appended to the end and the
classifiers would be like oh this is
looking bad oh look Pride and Prejudice
and then it would get through so spam
detection is in some ways a very poor
example of a canonical classification
problem because if you're trying to
build a classifier to detect if you're
building billion classifier to detect
the number seven the number seven is not
like trying to squirm its way out from
those pixels to avoid detection right
you can just get better at the task and
if you get perfect to the task great
spam is being generated by people who
are trying to defeat spam filters so
whatever technique you use whatever
features you use you're gonna capture
those kinds of spam emails others are
gonna make it through and spammers are
gonna double down on what's working and
so you get Pride and Prejudice at the
end when you're looking for language but
then suddenly you start using methods
like primarily looking at sender
information and now you have spammers
who want to buy contact information or
whatever it is so they can spoof that
and so the if you have features that are
like you know did the same email get
sent to a lot of different people what
do spammers do they're gonna start
modifying that email in some templated
way now you have some feature that
detects templates now it's um there's
sort of an arms race here and so in that
sense over time spam classification
doesn't actually look like a standard
classification problem because it's
adversarial okay any questions before we
talk about generalization and
overfitting okay so in these images you
want to fit the hat right you don't want
to be too small because if you over fit
you're not going to be able to
generalize but you don't want a sort of
under fit either because then you're
going to fail to learn the information
that's actually in your training data
here's an example of this trade-off in
general we're going to do discrete
classification but for this example
let's imagine the thing we're trying to
do is to fit a curve to this data so I
could I can pick I can pick a model
you've probably done this in other
classes I could decide to fit a line I
could
they're curved I can fit different kinds
of models so one thing I could do is I
could fit a constant function what
constant function should I fit if I want
to optimize the fit so you say what is
the fit is the fit getting as close as
possible to the last dot hmm let's say
the fit is the thumb across all the data
points of the squared distance or
something so what is my constant
approximation to this somebody want to
hazard a guess let's call it five okay
imagine that was a straight line imagine
that was a slope zero line okay did I
fit something about this data yeah I fit
something about the data I fit and
basically it's mean did I capture the
major trends no this I would call this
underfitting
all right let's try again let's fit a
let's let's fit a linear function okay
close right it's a better fit than the
constant function notice that when I
went to linear function the space of
hypotheses grew instead of just lines
now it's like lines with slopes and
intercepts okay so as my space of
hypotheses grow in general there are
when there's more hypotheses I can fit
my data more closely all right I miss
something about it there's this sort of
like there's a sort of dip so maybe I
could go to a second-order function like
quadratic if I can draw this okay
quadratic I'm starting to fit my data
better could I fit it even more closely
yeah I could how about this degree 15
polynomial way better fit than the
quadratic so it's not just about fitting
your data it's about you can always fit
your data more it's about fitting your
data to the point where the patterns
that you are capturing are ones which
generalize to test and that's that's a
tricky balance this this is definitely
overfitting and so you can't basically
just judge by your training accuracy
which you can drive higher and higher
and higher how well you're doing you
need some measure of whether you've gone
too far in the fitting process and in
this case we talked about hyper
parameters a hyper parameter could be
something like what's the maximum degree
of polynomial
loud right and I could detect on
held-out data as as I'm adding more more
terms to the polynomial my training
accuracy or my training error the
residuals here they're getting smaller
and smaller and smaller but I can detect
that on some held out data suddenly it's
gone crazy because there's this point
here in the held out set and you're like
you're nowhere near it okay so that's
the general idea here but overfitting
shows up not just on these continuous
functions it also shows up on discrete
functions
it also shows up for example let's
imagine in a hypothetical digit
classification we might say here is an
image I've never seen before let's use
naive Bayes to classify it so what we do
we do our running total we'd say all
right well I I had before I look at any
features the numbers are the numbers two
and three let's say are equally likely
so let's multiply in evidence terms well
for each pixel for example this pixel
maybe this pixel is equally likely for a
three as a two okay so they're still
tied this pixel is much more likely for
a three than a two let's imagine so now
at this point I'm thinking this is
looking like a three and I would have a
bunch of these terms one for each
feature in this case maybe one for each
pixel alright for this one this pixel
being off is much more likely for a
three then a two because the two has
that diagonal line so so far three is
winning but eventually I'm going to get
to some pixel maybe like this one here
and in my training data this is almost
never on this is this is in a corner
where there's no number and maybe it
turns out that this number that this
picks will have to happen to be on once
or twice in the data for the digit two
but zero times in the data for digit
three so when I multiply together all
these probabilities which are all
roughly reasonable who's gonna win two
is gonna win because it isn't have that
zero well that's bad this is an example
of overfitting because this probability
versus this probability that is about
the idiosyncrasies of the samples I have
in my data whereas perhaps the fact that
you know this is 0.1 and this is 0.7
that might actually be us that might be
actually a more enduring fact that
transfers
my training - my test alright let's look
at examples of overfitting remember we
talked about what's the most likely word
given ham though what's the most likely
were given spam the I can instead ask
when I do these multiplications together
into that running product which are the
words which sort of swing the product
most one way or the other I can look at
odds ratios which is the ratio of the
probability in the two and if the ratio
is one it means it's equally likely
whether it's common or uncommon it
doesn't affect the competition it's
things that are more common in one than
the other that have a big impact on
these odds ratios so let's look at words
what do you think in my training data
for ham versus spam things with the
highest odds ratio for ham would be
these are things that are significantly
more likely for him than for spam words
like Gary except when I look at my data
it's actually a mess it turns out there
are a bunch of words in this data which
occur in spam once and occur in if you
occur in ham once in a current spam zero
and if you just say that the
probabilities in your model are the
probabilities in the data
you're gonna give probability 0 to a lot
of things through overfitting the
probability of Southwest which occurs
once in ham and 0 in spam it's not 0 in
spam just like that pixel being off
wasn't 0 for the number 3 it's just 0 in
my data it's really dangerous to give
things the probability 0 that's one of
many kinds of overfitting where the
exact details of which sample points you
drew when you collected your data get
captured to sort of a in a way that
doesn't generalize then there's gonna be
things in spam which are you know a
bunch of other things that occur once
and spam but never in ham so something
went wrong here what went wrong here is
really we should not go about giving
probability 0 to things that we haven't
seen just because we haven't seen them
yet and the exact mechanics of
overfitting are gonna vary from model to
model in naive Bayes probabilistic
models overfitting usually shows up a
sampling error which are sorry sampling
variance which usually shows up as
zeroes in your probability table for
other methods it's going to show up in
totally other way
okay all right we actually talked about
all of this so to do better we need to
smooth or regularize our estimates so
let's figure out some ways to do that to
just illustrate what it would look like
to limit to limit overfitting we already
know one kind of limitation of
overfitting we could take that
polynomial and we could limit the degree
of the polynomial that's shrinking the
hypothesis space as you shrink a
hypothesis space you or you you fit less
are you drinking too much you under fit
we could also do that with words we
could say I'm only actually interested
in the hundred most common words that
would be shrinking my hypothesis space
that's one way to do it
we can also regularize which is we can
try to come up with estimates for our
probabilities our weights in general
which are not completely driven by the
data but are also balanced against some
regularizing function or smoothing
function that makes things a little
flatter something that hedges so let's
take a look at the distribution of a
random variable let's sort of show why
we need to do these kinds of things how
are we going to figure out what the
what-what are and invariable is we can
do Alyssa tation right you can ask human
you can go to a doctor and say hey I'm
building a classifier what fraction of
people with meningitis will present with
a fever and a doctor can can give you a
guess right it may be qualitative you
could also do that empirically you could
use training data you could go collect a
bunch of records of patient patient
treatment or something like that and
this is basically what what learning
does you take your training data you
take the trends out of the training data
the simplest version of this is for each
outcome to look at the empirical rate so
for example if I am a jelly bean
counting if I'm a jelly bean counting
robot and I am trying to figure out in
this vat of jelly beans
how many Reds versus blues there are and
I draw three jelly beans and it's two
Reds and two blues well what can we do
there's the maximum likelihood estimate
or relative frequency estimate which
says okay the probabilities are just the
counts in the training data that means
the maximum likelihood probability of
red for this data is 2/3 is that right
well
the more samples I draw the more
accurate that's going to be in general
we don't have as many samples as we want
so we're gonna want to do something to
prevent things like zeros in these
estimates okay why is this called
maximum likelihood so here's my corpus
and call it D there's my corpus there
are a bunch of different probabilities I
could say for read I could say they're
5050 I could say it's a hundred percent
read for each probability I assigned to
read and one minus that goes to blue I
can compute the probability of D okay
that's something you could try writing
out for yourself of all of those
probabilities the one that matches the
frequency of the data is the one that
maximizes the probability of the data so
so that's a thing you can do and it's
totally reasonable but in practice you
need some smoothing so I guess we have
some Halloween ghost after all even
though we're now into the post Halloween
lectures but we just want we want no
surprises to our model we want our model
to assign probability to events it's
never seen so that one errant pixel or
word that is rare doesn't completely
Torpedo and otherwise very nuanced
balancing of evidence all right so what
was the maximum likely likelihood
estimate the maximum likelihood estimate
basically you have to work this out
right maybe we just go back and do it
real quick okay so let's say R is my
probability of red and one minus R is my
probability of blue what is the
probability of this data well it's
basically I got an R and then I got
another R and then I got the other thing
which is one minus R so as I change the
probability of red this term which is
the likelihood of the data is going to
go up and down and the balance the point
where that's going to be maximized you
can sort you know if you if you sort of
set it up carefully there take
derivatives find the extreme point
you'll get the relative frequency answer
out so the maximum likelihood estimate
it says find me the parameters
probabilities which make the data most
likely well that's fine to make the data
likely but I actually don't want that
that's not what I want what I want is to
come
sitter the problem of given my data
which parameters are most likely sounds
like it's basically the same thing and
it almost is except for one term so what
I really want is something like a
posterior estimate a maximum a
posteriori estimate which says I would
like to theta which is most likely given
my data what's that mean well we can use
Bayes rule to write that that means find
me the parameters which maximize the
product of this which is what we were
doing before this knew this denominator
here doesn't matter it's just some
constant that doesn't change as I change
theta but there's this extra term P of
theta and so what this says is it says
if I want to know what parameter what
probability is most likely I need to
weigh the likelihood of the data against
how likely I think that parameter is in
the first place and if I think zeros
aren't very likely then there's gonna
have to be some balance that is struck
okay so this doesn't have a closed form
solution without giving you more
information you can look at cs2 81a to
learn a lot more about that but here's a
basic idea of how you might approach it
this actually due to Laplace hundreds of
years ago now who's a philosopher who
kind of worried about things like well
how do I estimate the probability like
what is the probability of the Sun will
rise in the morning every morning so far
it's risen so probability one but I know
that can't be right because at some
point perhaps quite far out the Sun will
once not rise so I know that I know that
this estimate is wrong and I need some
way of mechanically incorporating the
fact that there are events which I
haven't seen but which I know to be
possible or at least that I'd like to
model as being possible why do we want
to do this well we'd rather not have our
robots just like totally freaked out at
unseen events though I suppose actually
if the Sun doesn't show up that's
probably grounds for free camp
so here's Laplace's procedural estimate
Laplace said well basically it's a
pretty good idea to take into account
the problem
in your observation but you should hold
out an extra observation for everything
you didn't see to reflect it potentially
happening at some point in the future so
basically add one to all your counts
including the ones that are zero so the
maximum likelihood estimate for red red
blue if I say what's the probability of
red , probability of blue two-thirds
one-third Laplace would say instead of
saying there's two of one and one of the
other which normalized this is a
two-thirds one-third add one to each so
instead of two Reds there's three
there's those ones plus my pretend red
and instead of one blue there's two
because I have my pretend blue now what
do I get I get three-fifths and
two-fifths red is still winning but this
distribution has gotten flatter and if
there had been zero blues it would no
longer have be given probability zero so
pretty reasonable we can do better we
can say we imagine you see each outcome
K times instead of one time because
maybe one time is too many or maybe it's
too few we can adjust formally if you
derive this this comes from adjusting
the strength of the prior and you can
you can imagine wanting to do more or
less than adding one and so if I add 0
if I take little classes extended method
and I add zero then I just get my 2/3
1/3 estimate from red red blue we know
if we add a count of one and we pretend
well there's one phantom are and one
phantom blue will get 3/5 but if I had
100 there's now a hundred of these
there's a hundred of those ARS and
there's a whole bunch of Blues - and
there's a hundred blues now how many
Reds do I have well I do my computations
as if I had one hundred and two Reds and
101 blues and suddenly even though there
are still more Reds and blues in my
posterior estimate here it's pretty
close to 50/50 so as I crank up K I have
a stronger prior and I fit less if I
crank down ki fit more and so I now I
have a dial which can trade off the
amount of fitting against generalization
okay
it is it is certainly not the case that
this is the only way to estimate
probabilities or the estimating
probabilities is the only kind of
machine learning we will see a whole
bunch of other things in the next few
lectures but what is important is that
in general there will be knobs you can
turn which cause you to do more
generalization or less generalization
and that can control fitting okay not
going to talk about the conditionals
room I think we have skipped this too
all right so let's go to real naive
Bayes so in a real classification
problem you have to smooth if you're
gonna use naive Bayes and so for example
I can go into my my spam and instead of
computing odds ratios on the maximum
likelihood or empirical relative
frequency estimates I can instead do
some smoothing and see after that
smoothing what what has the biggest odds
ratio and suddenly things that only
occurred once they don't percolate to
the top because they haven't occurred
enough to overwhelm that flat prior that
I'm associating them with so this is the
top of the odds ratios for ham on the
left and favoring spam on the right some
of these maybe make sense like there it
is money fries probably in there
somewhere if you see money that's a good
sign that it's spam or capital order or
credit presumably credit card I don't
know there's some things that indicate
ham this looks like general English text
what is going on there
how veticon versus for Donna spammers
used for Donna what is this this
reflects the default fonts that were in
use at this time across different
platforms and so one of the things you
find in machine learning is you know
what you think the features are gonna be
or rather which features are gonna be
useful but you might be wrong sometimes
things surprise you and that's why it's
always good to like actually look into
your model and see what has been learned
here is there something that I can learn
about this problem from what the machine
has learned about the problem all right
let's see
we talked about tuning so let's say I
build my naive Bayes model for spam four
digits whatever I've got my features
let's say they're mostly words and
pixels though in your projects you'll
see you can do better and I have some
tuning to do like for you know again
this is for naive Bayes every method is
gonna have a different incarnation of
this but I can change the strength of my
priors if I crank K to zero
I'm not gonna smooth it all and I'm
gonna fit my data very well if I crank K
to a million I'm definitely knocking
over fit but I'm also not gonna learn
anything so somewhere in between is the
right amount how do I figure out the
right amount well I could look at my
training data and see where am I more
accurate but the K that's gonna be most
accurate on my training data is zero
because that's that's what actually fits
the training data best that's the
maximum likelihood estimate and so what
you need to have is an addition to your
parameters which are these kind of basic
counts and things like that that you're
gonna set on your training data you need
to have some held out data that you can
do things like re given these counts how
much smoothing am I gonna do what's that
right balance between fitting enough but
not too much so we learn our parameters
from the training data and with what the
is actually the parameters is going to
append on the model we tuned them on
some different data like some held out
data because otherwise you'll get crazy
results and then eventually you're gonna
take the best value do some final tests
two final tests test run okay I'm gonna
say a very little bit about features
because I think it's important for when
we start to get to neural nets where the
story here is gonna change so in general
your model is gonna make errors we're
gonna talk more about this starting next
lecture but your models gonna make
errors here are some examples of errors
that the quick knife based system I
whipped up does makes on this training
set here's one example your global scape
customer we've partnered with scan soft
to offer you something and then there's
this other one that's also an error
which is to receive your thirty dollar
Amazon promotional certificate click on
this okay one with spam that should have
been ham on his hand that should have
been spam these are tricky cases and
it's actually very hard to tell from the
words which ones which and in fact in
this case it might actually just be
noise in the data so what are you gonna
do when you make errors well
one thing is in general you're gonna
need more features so in spam
classification we found out that it
wasn't enough to just look at words you
got to look at other sort of metadata
from the ecosystem for digit recognition
you do a sort of more advanced things
than just looking pixels and pixels
where you look at things like edges and
loops and things like that try to do
things that are invariant to rotation
and scale and all of that the vision
folks think about you can add these as
sources of information by just adding
variables into your naive Bayes model
but we'll also talk in the next few
classes about ways to add these more
flexibly and also ways in ways to induce
these alright I'm gonna stop there for
today and as you go please come up and
grab some more candy
thank you